https://apra.me **\(+358 417 917 861** □ apramey.bhat@aalto.fi in linkedin.com/in/aprameybhat Servin Maijan Tie 10, Espoo, Finland

Apramey Bhat

Summary

A master's student at Aalto University with a focus on security and cloud computing, coupled with four years of experience as a software engineer. I am looking for a new challenge in progressive, customer-focused, and industrial researchoriented firm where I can maximize my passion for technology and broaden my understanding of user-centered techniques.

Keywords from my LinkedIn recommendations describe me as: soft spoken, humble, blends with the team, takes ownership, dedicated, committed, quick learner, go an extra mile to close tasks, logical reasoning, go to person ...

Education

Aug 2022 -

Aalto University, Espoo, Finland

Present

Master's Program in Security and Cloud Computing - SECCLO (Erasmus Mundus Joint Master's Degree)

2014 - 2018

SDM College of Engineering and Technology, Dharwad, India. Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science. (Grade: 9.03/10)

Professional Experience

Sep 2022 -Oct 2022

(Part time)

Teaching Assistant, Aalto University

School of Science, Espoo, Finland

- Responsible for assisting students with their assignments for the course CS-C3130 Information Security
- Assignments: Access Control, SQL Injection, Password Cracking, Web Insecurity, Buffer Overrun, XSS

Dec 2020 -Aug 2022

(Full time)

Senior Software Engineer, First American Financial Corporation

Business Technology Solutions Team, Bengaluru, India

- Responsible for architecting and developing solutions for a data reconciliation project involving inhouse product integrations
- Application Security:
 - Resolved multiple application vulnerabilities such as Cross-site scripting XSS, External XML Entities, and SQL Injection etc.
 - Completed Veracode Application Security Professional exam with 94.7%, which involved 35 courses [Transcript]
- Full Stack Development & Cloud Solutions:
 - Designed and developed a suite of 50+ REST APIs and services with serverless and microservices architecture
 - Developed a Rule Engine based on Rete Algorithm for on-the-go reconciliation of financial data between multiple systems
- The data reconciliation project saved around \$22M per year
- Tech Stack: .Net Core, AWS Cloud Services, Angular, TIBCO EMS, OAuth 2.0

July 2018 -Dec 2020 (Full time)

Product Engineer, INSZoom (A Mitratech Company)

Product Development Team, Bengaluru, India

- Application Security:
 - Integrated INSZoom with monitoring services like *Elmah* and *NewRelic*, to get the streamlined error and vulnerability reports
 - Identified and solved multiple **CWE** listed vulnerabilities found in the product
- Full Stack Development & Cloud Solutions:
 - Part of 20+ full stack revamp projects that involved reactive frontend framework and microservices architecture; Laid the groundwork for **x10** traffic scale into the newly designed product
- Promoted to Core Tech Team and was involved in various proof-of-concept projects
- Tech Stack: Net Core, Net WebAPI, SQL, Vue.js, Vuex, Webpack, RabbitMQ, Bootstrap, Elastic Search, AWS S3, Azure

Feb 2018 -May 2018 (Part time)

Product Engineer - Intern, INSZoom (A Mitratech Company)

Product Development Team, Bengaluru, India

- Worked on fixing vulnerabilities and bugs of various modules of the product, thereby increasing code quality and KPI of modules
- Tech Stack: ASP.Net MVC, SQL, .Net WebAPI, JavaScript, JQuery, Azure

Relevant Skills

Frameworks Database .Net Core, .Net Web API, Node.js, Flask, Vue.js, React, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, xUnit, Caffe

Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB

Tools & Lib. Github, Git, Dapper, Mog, Axios, TIBCO EMS, RabbitMQ, Docker, OpenCV

AWS Cloud Solutions (EC2, S3, SNS, SQS, Lambda, RDS, Step Functions, Cloudwatch), Google Cloud Platform Cloud (ComputeEngine, Firebase, Tensorflow), Terraform Scripting

Languages C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Java, C

Extracurricular Activities & Achievements

Volunteering

- Volunteer at **Slush**, participant and volunteer at **Junction** [2022]
- Teaching Assistant at Google Developer Days India [2017]
- Student Facilitator for Google Applied CS Skills with Android at SDMCET [Success Story] [2017-2018]
- Event coordinator and graphic designer at **Insignia** for a stretch of 4 years at SDMCET [2014 -2018]
- Internshala Student Partner for SDMCET Dharwad [2017-2018]

Trainings & Certifications

- Veracode certified Application Security Professional [Feb'21]
- Architecting on AWS, AWS Technical Essentials, AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials [Sep'21]

Awards

- Top Performer Q1 2022 First American Financial Corporation [2022]
- Zoom Star Top 3 engineers in INSZoom to get awarded by the CEO [2020]
- Zoom Miles Champion (thrice) Quarterly Award presented in INSZoom [2018-2020]
- Undergraduate final year thesis project was selected as **Top 3000 Startups in India** by IIM Calcutta, India [2018]

Test Scores • TOEFL iBT – **102/120** (R:22, L:29, S:23, W:28) [Issued on: May 17, 2021]

Spoken Languages

- English (Fluent)
- Kannada, Hindi, Tulu (Native)
- Finnish (Beginner)

References

(Contact info available on request)

- Vinay Kalasannavar (Tech Lead, Mitratech)
- Anil Pujeri (Engineering Manager, SenseHawk)
- Dr. Shrihari Joshi (Professor, SDMCET)

